Guide to the Joseph W. Reed and George Creeger Collection of Human Likenesses, 1840 - 1900
Joseph W. Reed and George Creeger Collection of Human Likenesses 1840-1900
Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)
2012-13
3
7
The collection contains primarily nineteenth century individual portrait photographs. A small portion of photographs are of identified individuals. When the photographer or sitter is known, the identification is noted in the listing. The images include daguerreotypes, ambrotypes, tintypes (also called ferrotypes), card images, and card images in an album. Most dates are approximate ones determined by internal evidence.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisitions Information
Wesleyan professors Joseph W. Reed and George Creeger collected these images over many years. They donated the collection to Wesleyan University Special Collections & Archives in 2012.
Collection Overview
The collection contains primarily nineteenth century individual portrait photographs. A small portion of photographs is of identified individuals. When the photographer or sitter is known, the identification is noted in the listing. The images include daguerreotypes, ambrotypes, tintypes (also called ferrotypes), card images, and card images in an album. Most dates are approximate ones determined by internal evidence. Photographers are noted when known.
The album is 50 pages with two carte-de-visite to a page. Annotations identify some images and/or photographers. Pencil erasures at top of some pages, apparently names of individuals depicted in images once in the album. It is in poor condition with detached covers; repairs to front and back pages, and spine, using canvas; the lower latch is missing.
The images are organized by type, cased images precede uncased images; identified images precede unidentified images. Unidentified images are arranged by size, then in approximate chronological order.
Collection Arrangement
The items arranged invidually by type and date.
Online Catalog Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Portrait photography.; Ambrotypes.; Card photographs.; Composite photographs.; Daguerreotypes--1840-1860.; Photogravure.; Tintype.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Series I. Daguerrotype
  - Jeffers, 1840-1850 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Woman, head and shoulders portrait, wearing bonnet
    2 1/2 x 3 inch exterior
    Front case cover missing
  - RbbS & Co, 229 Broadway, 1845-1855 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Woman wearing bonnet, seated
    Tinted, 2 x 2 1/2 inch exterior
    Mat in pressed brass, without case
  - E.D. Ritton (?), 1845-1860 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Woman seated, wearing lace “petal” collar
    Tinted, 1/9 plate, 2 1/4 x 3 inch exterior
    Brass mat and decorative frame, brown decorative case with gilt detailing at edge.
  - Samuel Roberson, head and shoulders portrait, 1850-1860 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    1/6 plate, 3 3/4 x 3 1/4 inch exterior
    Paper pinned to inner cover: Samuel Roberson Father of Luther A. Roberson
    Image has tarnishing
  - Samuel Roberson, wearing top hat, head and shoulders portrait, 1850-1860 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Paper pinned to inner cover: Samuel Roberson Father
    Image has tarnishing, front cover detached
  - Woman wearing bonnet, head and shoulders portrait, 1845-1850 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Tinted, 2 1/2 x 3 inch exterior
    Plain brass mat
  - Man wearing cravat, head and shoulders portrait, 1845-1850 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Image quality poor, apparent tarnishing, hinge repaired with black tape
  - Boy in plaid shirt, seated, 1845-1855 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Mat in brass
  - Woman seated with child on her lap, 1855-1865 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Decorative embossed brass mat and frame
  - Girl and boy, sister and brother?, seated, 1855-1865 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    1/6 plate, 3 x 3 1/4 inch exterior
    Nonpareil brass mat, without case
    Image tarnished at edges
  - Man, head and shoulders portrait, 1855-1865 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Tinted, 1/9 plate, 2 1/2 x 3 inch exterior
    Decorative, embossed nonpareil mat and frame
  - Man, head and shoulders portrait, 1855-1865 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    1/9 plate, 2 1/2 x 3 inch exterior
    Nonpareil mat and decorative brass frame
  - Woman wearing bonnet and pin, 1840-1850 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Octagonal brass mat
    Cover hinge repaired with black tape
  - Man, head and shoulders portrait, 1840-1850 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Tinted, 1/6 plate, 3 3/4 x 3 1/4 inch exterior
    Image has tarnishing, faded
    Front cover in poor condition, with leather torn at some edges showing wood
  - Boy with arm resting on chair arm, seated, 1840-1850 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Image is faded and has tarnishing, front cover lacking
  - Woman wearing glasses and bonnet, head and shoulders portrait, 1845-1855 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Elderly woman wearing glasses and bonnet, head and shoulders portrait, 1845-1855 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Brass mat and frame, image faded
    Front cover lacking
  - Woman with shawl seated, 1845-1855 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Front case cover missing; notable fading on left side of image
  - Girl, 1845-1860 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Decorative pressed brass mat and frame, cased
    [Note: apparent source for tintype copy]
  - Woman seated, with shawl over one shoulder, 1845-1855 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Octagonal brass mat and frame
    Image faded and scratched, front cover lacking
  - Young woman seated, 1845-1860 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Brass arched mat and embossed frame
  - Man, three-quarters head and shoulders portrait, 1845-1860 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Front and back covers separated, black tape at hinge
  - Woman seated, wearing pin at high collar, 1850-1860 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Nonpareil brass frame
    Cover hinge repaired with black tape, inner front liner lacking
  - Two women seated, holding hands, 1850-1860 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Girl seated, wearing polka dot dress, 1850-1860 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Brass mat and frame
    Cover hinge repaired with black tape, front and back covers mismatched
  - Woman, man, in facing head and shoulders portraits, both seated each holding a book, man in Anglican collar, single case, 1850-1860 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Nonpareil brass mats and frames, Union case
    Images in good condition
  - Man seated, three-quarters portrait, 1850-1860 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Image spotted, cover hinge repaired with black tape
  - Man with moustache, seated, 1850-1860 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Nonpareil brass mat and frame
    Image has tarnishing, spots
  - Man and woman seated, man’s arm around woman’s shoulder, 1850-1860 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Man seated, hands clenched, 1855-1865 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Case presented as book, decorative mother of pearl inlay to front cover
    Front cover detached, black tape at hinge
  - Woman and man seated, woman’s hand on man’s shoulder, 1855-1865 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Union case, front cover lacking
  - Girl seated, with hand on draped object, 1855-1865 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Girl with ringlets seated, 1850-1855 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    1/6 plate, 3 1/2 x 3 1/4 inch exterior
    Decorative pressed paper mat
  - Woman seated, wearing plaid dress, 1855-1865 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Nonpareil decorative, embossed brass mat
    Image faded, front case cover missing
  - Man, head and shoulders portrait, 1845-1855 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Series II. Ambrotype
  - Clifford, “Ambrotype PA,” 1850-1855 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Woman with dangling earrings and brooch
    Tinted, 1/9 plate, 3 x 2 1/2 inch exterior
    Mat in brass, photographer’s name impressed in reverse
    Case hinge repaired with black tape
  - W.B. Eastman, Boston (?), 1845-1855 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Man and woman seated
    External brass frame and paper (on back) with photographer’s information not concurrent to image
  - G.G. Mason, Springfield, Mass., 1855-1865 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Woman with ringlets seated
    Tinted, 1/9 plate, 2 1/2 x 2 inch exterior
    Mat in paper, without case. Decorative brass frame
    Frame may not be concurrent to image
  - Boy seated, leaning against table, 1850-1865 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    External brass frame not original
  - Boy standing, leaning against table, 1850-1860 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Tinted, 1/9 plate, 3 x 2 1/4 inch exterior
    Mat and framed in pressed brass
  - Woman seated, wearing dress with white collar, 1855-1865 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Decorative brass mat and frame
    Front cover missing
  - Man seated, wearing coat and overcoat, head and shoulders portrait 1855-1865 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Tinted, 1/9 plate, 2 ½ x 3 inch exterior
  - Man, head and shoulders portrait, 1855-1865 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Woman in large cape and bonnet, seated with hands crossed, 1850-1860 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Man, seated, 1850-1865 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Brass frame
    Dark backing flaking, affecting image quality
  - Woman and man seated, his arm behind her back, 1850-1860 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Embossed brass mat and frame
  - Girl seated with arm resting on table, 1855-1865 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Woman in large lace collar and bow, seated, 1855-1865 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Embossed frame and mat may not be concurrent to image, resting in case back cover
  - Man seated with arm resting on table, wearing overcoat and large cravat, 1855-1865 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Man seated with arm resting on table, 1855-1865 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Front cover not joined to hinge
  - Girl seated, arm resting on table, 1855-1865 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Man, head and shoulders portrait, 1855-1865 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Tinted, 1/6 plate, 3 1/4 x 3 inch exterior
    Mat in decorative pressed brass
    Scratches on backing affect image
    Brass frame not concurrent to image, lacking frame
  - Toddler seated on mother’s lap, mother’s face not in view, 1855-1865 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Tinted, 1/4 plate, 4 3/4 x 3 3/4 inch exterior
    Front cover detached
- Series III. Tintype
  - Women, in facing head and shoulders portraits, each seated, 1855-1865 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Decorative embossed brass mat and frame, Union case
    Corrosion to left mat, right image faded
  - Man, three-quarters head and shoulders portrait, 1855-1865 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Tinted, 3 1/4 x 2 1/2 inch exterior
    Decorative brass frame
    Oval blue velvet case not concurrent to image
  - Girl, head and shoulders portrait, 1855-1865 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    Tinted, 3 3/4 x 3 1/4 inch exterior
    Decorative embossed brass mat and frame, case front lacking
    [Note: apparent copy of ambrotype]
  - Man in Union uniform, seated, arm resting on chair back, 1860-1869 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    Embossed brass decorative mat not concurrent to image, resting in case back cover
  - Woman, head and shoulders portrait, 1860-1870 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    1/6 plate, 5 x 4 1/4 inch exterior
    Image backing dented
  - Toddler, seated, 1860-1870 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    1/6 plate, 3 1/4 x 2 3/4 inch exterior
    Lacks case
  - Man seated, wearing hat, 1870-1880 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Tinted, 1/6 plate, 3 1/4 x 2 3/4 inch exterior
    Decorative embossed mat
    Lacks usual frame, lacks case
  - Two men seated, both smoking cigars, 1870-1880 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Tinted, 4 1/4 x 3 1/2 inch exterior
    Decorative pressed brass mat and frame
    Emulsion lifting from backing, lacks case
- Series IV. Carte-de-visite
  - Haines & Wickes, Albany, NY, 1860-1870 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Mrs. Charles Massoineau
  - G. W. Hennigar, Middletown, Conn., 1850-1870 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Freddie S. 4 yrs old
  - Lewis, New Britain, Conn., 1870-1890 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Ida L. F. Benedict, head and shoulders portrait
  - Lewis, New Britain, Conn., 1870-1890 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Katie A. Callahan, head and shoulders portrait
  - Lewis, New Britain, Conn., 1870-1890 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Jessie M. Cone, head and shoulders portrait
  - Lewis, New Britain, Conn., 1870-1890 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Nellie A. Keeler, head and shoulders portrait
  - Lewis, New Britain, Conn., 1870-1890 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Anna M. Murray, head and shoulders portrait
  - Lewis, New Britain, Conn., 1870-1890 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Lena M. Rettman, head and shoulders portrait
  - Lewis, New Britain, Conn., 1870-1890 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Jennie B. Roberts, head and shoulders portrait
  - Lewis, New Britain, Conn., 1870-1890 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Anna C. Webster, head and shoulders portrait
  - Prescott & White, Hartford, Conn., 1880-1890 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Joel Hall
    Signed on verso: Joel Hall, Marlboro, Conn.
  - Geo. Anderson, Norwich, Conn., 1860-1880 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Man, head and shoulders portrait
  - A.A. Turner, D. Appleton & Co., New York, NY, 1860-1880 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Woman, head and shoulders portrait
  - Barhyot’s, Rochester, NY, 1870-1880 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - W.F. Burrows, Middletown, Conn., 1860-1870 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Baby, seated in high chair
  - Fanny Dahl, Fotografisk Atelier, Randers [Denmark], 1870-1890 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - D.D.T. Davie, Cuba, NY, 1865-1880 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Davidson, New Britain, Conn., 1870-1880 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Young woman, head and shoulders portrait
    Seven unidentified women
  - Davidson, New Britain, Conn., 1870-1880 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    Four unidentified men
  - Geo. Degen, New York, NY, 1850-1870 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    Woman, standing, wearing hoop skirt, cape, bonnet and veil
  - Durgan, Norwich, Conn, 1865-1880 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Fredericks, New York, NY, 1850-1870 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    Man, face added to photograph of cartoon body
  - Laighton Brothers, Norwich, Conn., 1880-1890 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Lewis, New Britain, Conn., 1870-1890 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    Eleven unidentified women
  - F. Lewis, Cawker City, Kansas, 1870-1880 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    Man, seated
  - F. Lewis, Cawker City, Kansas, 1885-1895 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Julius Parish, Friendship, NY, 1860-1880 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    Woman and man, man seated
  - G. Penabert & Cie, Paris, France, 1860-1880 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Prior Bros., Providence, RI, 1870-1890 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    Woman, standing with hands crossed at chair back
  - Rodgers, Hartford, Conn., 1880-1890 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    Girl, head and shoulders portrait
  - Rodgers Photographic Palace, Hartford, Conn., 1880-1890 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - I.H. Stoddard, Ansonia, Conn., 1870-1880 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - C. Townsend, Willimantic, Conn., 1870-1890 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    Two unidentified men
  - Upton, Oberlin, Ohio, 1880-1890 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Worden, 1870-1880 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Worden, 1870-1880 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Mrs. John Curtis, 1865-1870 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Charles Massoinneau, 1865-1870 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Bayard Taylor, 1878 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    On verso: “Given to Martinas Robert (?) by Bayard Taylor March 1, 1878 Beardsley”
  - Two men seated, 1870-1880 (Box 5, Folder 40)
- Series V. Cabinet
  - H.L. Bundy, Hartford Conn., 1880-1890 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    Jennie Vera Stearns, Andover, Conn.
  - C.H. Crandall, Lakeside Park, NY, 1880-1900 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    Rena and unidentified woman, head and shoulders portrait
    Image marked with ink
  - Dally, Fremont, Neb., 1880-1900 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    John Clifton Chapman, age 1 year 14 days
  - H.M. Fisher, Gresham, Neb., 1890-1900 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    John Clifton Chapman, age 3 mo., 1 da.
  - Hutchings Railroad Photo Car, 1870-1890 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    May Cook, Doinpham, Neb.
  - Altman & Edelman, Battle Creek, Mich., 1890-1900 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    Two girls in white, one standing, one seated on chair back
  - Brewer’s, Belfast, NY, 1870-1880 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Cudding, Bolivar, NY, 1870-1890 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    Boy, head and shoulders portrait
  - Cudding, Bolivar and Friendship, NY, 1880-1890 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    Boy, standing, legs crossed, leaning on chair
  - Cudding, Bolivar, NY, 1880-1890 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    (Same man as Ward, Kingston, NY, man, bedecked with IOGT [International Order of Good Templars] convention ribbons)
  - DeLamater, Hartford, Conn., 1890-1900 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    Girl seated, hands in lap
  - Durgan, Norwich, Conn., 1880-1890 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    Image faded
  - Durgan, Norwich, Conn., 1880-1900 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    Man with young boy seated on his knee
  - Elite Studio, Chicago, Ill., 1880-1890 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    Boy, standing, legs crossed, leaning on fringed chair
  - Elite Studio, Chicago, Ill., 1880-1890 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    Girl seated in fringed chair
  - N.B. Evans, Ceres, Penn., 1890-1900 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - N.B. Evans, Ceres, Penn., 1890-1900 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Halloway, Newport, RI, 1890-1900 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    Baby, seated on brocade covered chair
  - Keefer & Carson, Reading, Mich., 1890-1900 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    Man, standing, one hand behind back, one on draped rest
  - Laighton Bros., Norwich, Conn., 1890-1900 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    Baby, seated, wearing hat
  - Chas. G. Link, Pittsburgh, Penn., 1880-1900 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    Woman and man, head and shoulders portrait
  - J. O’Neil, New York, NY, 1870-1880 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - J. Parish, Friendship, NY, 1885-1895 (Box 5, Folder 63)
    Man seated in fringed chair
  - Phelps, New Haven, Conn., 1880-1900 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    Woman, standing
  - Rockwood, New York, NY, 1880-1890 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - D.C. Scott, Friendship, NY, 1890-1900 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Girl and boy, girl seated and boy standing
  - D.C. Scott, Friendship, NY, 1890-1900 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Woman and man, woman standing with hand at open book
  - St. John, Hartford, Conn., 1885-1900 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Townsend, Willimantic, Conn., 1890-1900 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - C. H. Townsend, Willimantic, Conn., 1870-1880 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Two unidentified women
  - C. H. Townsend, Willimantic, Conn., 1880-1890 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Boy, standing, forearm resting on draped chair
  - Ward, Kingston, NY, 1880-1890 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    Man with IOGT [International Order of Good Templars] ribbons
    (Same man as Cudding, Bolivar, NY man, head and shoulders portrait)
  - Woman, head and shoulders portrait, 1870-1890 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Three unidentified women
  - Woman seated with child leaning on her lap, 1880-1900 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Baby seated on fur-draped chair, 1890-1900 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Series VII. Victoria
  - Johnson Bros., St. Joseph, Mich., 1890-1900 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Johnson Bros., St. Joseph, Mich., 1890-1900 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Townsend, Willimantic, Conn., 1890-1900 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    Baby seated in wicker chair
- Series VIII. Other card photographs
  - Cudding, Friendship, NY, 1890-1900 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    Two girls, one standing, one seated in high chair
    4 1/2 x 3 1/2 inch
    Backing has decorative, gilt scalloped edging.
  - Cudding, Friendship, NY, 1890-1900 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    Baby seated, in white gown
    Backing has decorative, gilt scalloped edging
  - Baby seated on woman’s lap, woman’s face most obscured, 1890-1900 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    2 1/2 x 2 inch
  - Joannes Volpato. Raphael Santivs pinx in Adibus Vaticanis, 1860-1965 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    On verso: “32 // Caro Molini – accept this photograph of one of your // great namesakes pictures with the kindest regards of // ever sincerely yours – G. M. Curtis. // Rome April 18th – 1865 // The little head in the right hand corner of the picture // is his own -- // Scuola di Atene”
- Series IX. Tintypes
  - J. Beerwald, Philadelphia, Penn., 1860-1880 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    1/6 plate, 3 3/4 x 2 1/2 inch exterior
    Black paper enclosure with gold decorative print elements, cut oval mat
  - H.V. Harris, Portland, Maine, 1880-1890 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    Man seated, wearing houndstooth-checked pants
    Tinted, 4 x 2 1/2 inch exterior
    Embossed paper enclosure, “arch” mat
  - Postal Photo Co., Niagara Falls, NY (Box 6, Folder 20)
    Two young men, head and shoulders portrait
    3 x 2 1/4 inch
    Embossed paper enclosure with cut oval mat
  - G. Seaver, Jr., Pittsfield, Mass., 1865-1875 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    Man standing, hand on chair back
    4 x 2 1/4 inch exterior
    Embossed paper enclosure
    Plate bent at upper right corner
  - Clara, seated girl, 1860-1869 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    4 1/4 x 2 3/4 inch exterior
    Decorative paper enclosure with cut oval mat
  - Woman with lace collar, pin, and pendant necklace sitting on fringed arm chair, 1870-1885 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    4 x 2 1/2 inch exterior
    Scratches on image surface, lower corners bent
  - Man seated, forearm resting on table, other forearm missing, 1870-1885 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Man seated, wearing pince-nez, cane in one hand and top hat in other hand1880-1890 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    3 1/2 x 2 1/2 inch exterior
  - Man, with watch fob, seated in fringed arm chair, 1870-1885 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    3 1/2 x 2 1/2 inch
  - Man seated in fringed arm chair, 1870-1885 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    Tinted, 3 1/2 x 2 1/2 inch
    Some scratches on emulsion, dents to plate
  - Two men seated, both smoking cigars, 1880-1890 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Woman wearing elaborate bow, sitting on fringed arm chair, 1870-1885 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    Plate corners clipped diagonally
  - Boy seated on folding chair, backdrop edges in view, 1870-1890 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    Two diagonal dents
  - Boy seated on fringed arm chair, 1870-1890 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    Tinted, 2 1/2 x 4 inch
  - Boy in lace collar, seated on textile draped chair, 1870-1890 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    2 1/2 x 3 3/4 inch
    Partial fingerprint in emulsion of upper right edge
  - Boy in deep lace collar, seated on textile draped setting, 1870-1890 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    2 1/2 x 3 1/2 inch
  - Man seated with one hand on thigh and other over a book on the table, 1870-1885 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    Tinted, 3 1/2 x 2 inch
  - Woman standing with arm resting on draped object, 1870-1885 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Woman seated with standing man, his hand resting on her shoulder, 1865-1880 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    Tinted, 3 x 2 inch
    Some dents to plate, emulsion flaking and corrosion at edges
  - Girl and boy standing, both with hands crossed at waist, 1865-1880 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    Some dents to plate, scratches to the emulsion
  - Girl seated, flanked by two boys, 1870-1890 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    3 1/2 x 2 1/4 inch
    Partial fingerprint in upper right corner, oval mat markings
  - Two women at outdoor monument, one seated, one standing at a fence, 1870-1880 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    2 3/4 x 4 inch
    Backing unevenly trimmed
  - Group: three women standing behind three seated men and standing boy, 1870-1890 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    3 1/4 x 2 3/4 inch
    Emulsion rippled at left
  - Group seated outside: nine women and three men, 1870-1890 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    Backing dented and embossed, emulsion crackled
  - Woman with dangling earrings, head and shoulders portrait, 1865-1880 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    7 x 5 inch
    Emulsion scratched
  - Young woman seated, 1870-1880 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    Decorative paper enclosure with cut arch mat
- Series X. Photogravure
  - Isabel Somerset, 1895 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    [Women’s Christian Temperance Union of Connecticut Souvenir]
  - F.A. Vinal, Evangelist (Box 6, Folder 45)
    6 1/2 x 4 1/2 inch
  - William H. Vinal, Chorus leader and soloist (Box 6, Folder 46)
    7 x 4 1/4 inch
  - Frances Willard, 1895 (Box 6, Folder 47)
- Series XI. Cased images parts
  - Daguerrotype plates (2) (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Ambrotype glass with image, 1/9 plate, 2 x 2 1/2 inch (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Cased image brass mats (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Cased image embossed brass mats and frames (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Cased images detached case covers (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Cased images detached case covers (Box 6, Folder 53)
- Series XII. Photograph album
  - Photograph Album1858-1890 (Box 7, Photoalbum 1)